<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Wiki</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Data Science Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 10:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Architectures</title>
      <link>/posts/deep-architectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 10:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/deep-architectures/</guid>
      <description>In this blogpost we explore the most relevant Deep Learning Architectures and their use cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transfer Learning - Sneak Peek</title>
      <link>/posts/transfer-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/transfer-learning/</guid>
      <description>Transfer Learning is a field of Machine Learning that study how to gain knowledge from data and generalize to new related domains. Since the theme is so broad, we start by its definition and a shortened explanation on methods and scenarios, focusing on Deep Learning and finishing with an exploration of its advantages and limitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning End-to-end</title>
      <link>/posts/ml-end-to-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 23:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ml-end-to-end/</guid>
      <description>Being a data scientist is not only creating models but also understanding the Machine Learning pipeline. How can we productize Machine Learning? What is the infrastructure behind it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BERT: Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers</title>
      <link>/posts/bert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 15:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/bert/</guid>
      <description>BERT is a pre-training language model for NLP developed by Google, that has caused excitement in the ML field given its state-of-the-art results. In this post, we focus on summarizing the paper, assuming some NLP familiarity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>In a world packed of information, it is challenging to be aware of the latest technologies and innovations. For that reason, this wiki urge as a strategy to keep studying and summarize important concepts related to Data Science. In a word, it is a handy glossary of not so trivial terms that supports my Data Science profession.
Who am I? Name: Inês Gomes
Location: Porto (Portugal)
Academic Background: BSc./MSc. in Informatics and Computing Engineering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Content</title>
      <link>/pages/future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/future/</guid>
      <description>List of topics that I&amp;rsquo;m not comfortable with, but that I&amp;rsquo;d like to explore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>/pages/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/glossary/</guid>
      <description>Glossary with several platforms, tools, models and benchmarks. Just to be aware of the newest trends.
A Active Learning: process of prioritising the data which needs to be labelled in order to have the highest impact to training a supervised model.
AIBench: AI benchmarking suite that proposes ways to do fine-grained analysis of a given AI application.
Airflow (Apache): platform to programmatically author, schedule and monitor workflows as directed acyclic graphs (DAGs) of tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links to Knowledge</title>
      <link>/pages/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/links/</guid>
      <description>Internet is a powerful resource to share knowledge. With diverse contributors around the world and distinct channels to disseminate information (e.g., audio, text, video), it is crucial to select the most appropriate ones according to our purpose. So, on this page, I select the most valuable links to knowledge, that I have encountered during my research, study or spare time.
Blogposts Machine Learning:
 Engineering Uncertainty Estimation in Neural Networks for Time Series Prediction at Uber Scaling Uber’s Customer Support Ticket Assistant (COTA) System with Deep Learning Forecasting COVID-19 Interpretability A state-of-the-art open source chatbot  NLP:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>