<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Wiki</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Data Science Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 23:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning End-to-end</title>
      <link>/posts/ml-end-to-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 23:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ml-end-to-end/</guid>
      <description>Being a data scientist is not only creating models but also understanding the Machine Learning pipeline. How can we productize Machine Learning? What is the infrastructure behind it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BERT: Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers</title>
      <link>/posts/bert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 15:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/bert/</guid>
      <description>BERT is a pre-training language model for NLP developed by Google, that has caused excitement in the ML field given its state-of-the-art results. In this post, we focus on summarizing the paper, assuming some NLP familiarity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>In a world packed of information, it is challenging to be aware of the latest technologies and innovations. For that reason, this wiki urge as a strategy to keep studying and summarize important concepts related to Data Science. In a word, it is a handy glossary of not so trivial terms that supports my Data Science profession.
Who am I? Name: Inês Gomes
Location: Porto (Portugal)
Academic Background: BSc./MSc. in Informatics and Computing Engineering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Content</title>
      <link>/pages/future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/future/</guid>
      <description>List of topics that I&amp;rsquo;m not comfortable with, but that I&amp;rsquo;d like to explore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>/pages/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/glossary/</guid>
      <description>Glossary with several platforms, tools, models and benchmarks. Just to be aware of the newest trends.
A Airflow (Apache): platform created by community to programmatically author, schedule and monitor workflows. Is scalable, dynamic, extensible and elegant.
AutoML (Google): train high-quality custom machine learning models with minimal effort and machine learning expertise.
B Batch Jobs: jobs that can run without end user interaction, or can be scheduled to run as resources permit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links to Knowledge</title>
      <link>/pages/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/links/</guid>
      <description>Content  Blogposts Resources and Tutorials Papers Books Podcasts Newsletters and Blogs Courses Glossary  Internet is a powerful resource to share knowledge. With diverse contributors around the world and distinct channels to disseminate information (e.g., audio, text, video), it is crucial to select the most appropriate ones according to our purpose. So, on this page, I select the most valuable links to knowledge, that I have encountered during my research, study or spare time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>